Amanda Lemmons

I'm excited to be writing to apply for the Director of Europe/ North Africa position. I read the job description, and to be honest, the job sounds pretty wonderful. To begin with, I deeply understand the nomadic lifestyle, as I have been living in Spain and traveling around Europe for the past six years, visiting 5 of the 8 places listed on the itinerary. I also fully support the objective of Remote Year, as I believe that everyone needs to get out of his or her comfort zone and experience what the world has to offer.

I feel that I am uniquely prepared for the Director of Europe/ North Africa role for multiple reasons. First and foremost, I have experience managing a geographically dispersed team. While working at Iberostar, one of my responsibilities included collaborating with our quality mangers, located throughout North and South America, to improve and redesign our strategy to better serve our guests. We also introduced a new initiative program targeted at our hotel employees, with the goal of improving and enhancing our guest's experiences while on vacation.

If given this opportunity, I am confident that with the combination of my current skill set and my desire to make Remote Year the best travel experience possible, I will be an incredible asset to your team moving forward.

I look forward to hearing from you.

Best, Amanda Lemmons

WORK EXPERIENCE

ShoeSize.Me

Barcelona, Spain

Amanda Lemmons

February 2016 – August 2016

Ruby on Rails Full Stack Developer

- Developed, implemented and maintained new features to the back-end of the web application
- Debugged medium sized back-end
- Maintained and enhanced current applications to ensure the ability to function flawlessly while scaling

Freelance Web Developer

Palma de Mallorca, Spain

January 2015 – Present

Ruby on Rails Full Stack Developer

- Work independently to develop and ship fast, production-quality full-stack applications with Ruby on Rails
- Developed ability to learn, problem solve and troubleshoot from documentation and direct implementation

Iberostar Hotel and Resorts

Palma de Mallorca, Spain

September 2012 – November 2014

Community Manager

- \bullet Leader of the social media team organized, developed and analyzed content leading to an overall increased engagement of 460%
- Worked closely with advertising agencies to create, execute and analyze social media
- Assisted with the global brand marketing campaign. Analyzed campaign results with Google Analytics and determined the appropriate measures to adapt the campaign plan mid launch which increased sale profits by 3400%
- Collaborated with the design, layout and functionality of the new corporate Marketing website. Supervised the uploading and testing of the newly launched website

Spanish Ministry of Education

Palma de Mallorca, Spain

October 2010 – May 2012

Auxiliar de Conversación (Teaching Assistant)

- Instructed English courses to international business professionals to help improve and refine English communication skills
- Developed lesson plans and led discussions to classrooms of 30+ Spanish-speaking students

Examples of Freelance Projects

Conversation class.es Full Stack Developer

- A web application built in Rails that allows English teachers in Spain connect with students
- Teachers are able to set a calendar of their availability and the students can book directly with a teacher. Payments are made through PayPal or Stripe.
- The students can directly message other students within the app to arrange study times.

Loslogin.com

Backend Developer

- Built for a loan originator that needed a website where she could securely input client information and this would auto-populate her documents
- Integrated with RightSignature API so clients can sign on a tablet

Johnscar.com

Full Stack Developer (currently working on site)

- Website has a backend built with Ruby with ecommerce section. Clients will be able to pay to download an eBook
- Will redesign the look and feel of the site.

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Austin

Amanda Lemmons

BS, Communication Studies: Corporate Communication | May 2010

Minor, Business: McCombs School of Business

Study Abroad: University Autonoma of Barcelona | Summer 2008

SKILLS

Back End: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Middleman

Front End: HTML, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap, jQuery & JavaScript, Responsive Designs

Database: PostgresQL

Version Control: Git & Github

Deploying: Heroku **Testing:** MiniTest

Business: Sales, Marketing and Promotions, Customer Service, Training, Administration

Language: Advanced Spanish proficiency, Basic French